<metadata xml:lang="en"><Esri><CreaDate>20160114</CreaDate><CreaTime>11013600</CreaTime><ArcGISFormat>1.0</ArcGISFormat><ArcGISstyle>FGDC CSDGM Metadata</ArcGISstyle><SyncOnce>FALSE</SyncOnce><DataProperties><itemProps><itemName Sync="TRUE">nlcd2011_usfs_prusvi_canopy_analytical.img</itemName><itemLocation><linkage Sync="TRUE">file://R:\TCC2011_Islands\Caribbean\FINAL_TCC_IMAGES\ImagePreparation\Analytical\nlcd2011_usfs_prusvi_canopy_analytical.img</linkage><protocol Sync="TRUE">Local Area Network</protocol></itemLocation><nativeExtBox><westBL Sync="TRUE">3042585.000000</westBL><eastBL Sync="TRUE">3407865.000000</eastBL><southBL Sync="TRUE">-78285.000000</southBL><northBL Sync="TRUE">61395.000000</northBL><exTypeCode Sync="TRUE">1</exTypeCode></nativeExtBox><imsContentType Sync="TRUE">002</imsContentType></itemProps><coordRef><type Sync="TRUE">Projected</type><geogcsn Sync="TRUE">GCS_North_American_1983</geogcsn><csUnits Sync="TRUE">Linear Unit: Meter (1.000000)</csUnits><projcsn Sync="TRUE">Albers_Conical_Equal_Area</projcsn><peXml Sync="TRUE">&lt;ProjectedCoordinateSystem xsi:type='typens:ProjectedCoordinateSystem' xmlns:xsi='http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance' xmlns:xs='http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema' xmlns:typens='http://www.esri.com/schemas/ArcGIS/10.0'&gt;&lt;WKT&gt;PROJCS[&amp;quot;Albers_Conical_Equal_Area&amp;quot;,GEOGCS[&amp;quot;GCS_North_American_1983&amp;quot;,DATUM[&amp;quot;D_North_American_1983&amp;quot;,SPHEROID[&amp;quot;GRS_1980&amp;quot;,6378137.0,298.257222101]],PRIMEM[&amp;quot;Greenwich&amp;quot;,0.0],UNIT[&amp;quot;Degree&amp;quot;,0.0174532925199433]],PROJECTION[&amp;quot;Albers&amp;quot;],PARAMETER[&amp;quot;false_easting&amp;quot;,0.0],PARAMETER[&amp;quot;false_northing&amp;quot;,0.0],PARAMETER[&amp;quot;central_meridian&amp;quot;,-96.0],PARAMETER[&amp;quot;standard_parallel_1&amp;quot;,29.5],PARAMETER[&amp;quot;standard_parallel_2&amp;quot;,45.5],PARAMETER[&amp;quot;latitude_of_origin&amp;quot;,23.0],UNIT[&amp;quot;Meter&amp;quot;,1.0]]&lt;/WKT&gt;&lt;XOrigin&gt;-16901100&lt;/XOrigin&gt;&lt;YOrigin&gt;-6972200&lt;/YOrigin&gt;&lt;XYScale&gt;266467840.99085236&lt;/XYScale&gt;&lt;ZOrigin&gt;-100000&lt;/ZOrigin&gt;&lt;ZScale&gt;10000&lt;/ZScale&gt;&lt;MOrigin&gt;-100000&lt;/MOrigin&gt;&lt;MScale&gt;10000&lt;/MScale&gt;&lt;XYTolerance&gt;0.001&lt;/XYTolerance&gt;&lt;ZTolerance&gt;0.001&lt;/ZTolerance&gt;&lt;MTolerance&gt;0.001&lt;/MTolerance&gt;&lt;HighPrecision&gt;true&lt;/HighPrecision&gt;&lt;/ProjectedCoordinateSystem&gt;</peXml></coordRef><RasterProperties><General><PixelDepth Sync="TRUE">8</PixelDepth><HasColormap Sync="TRUE">TRUE</HasColormap><CompressionType Sync="TRUE">RLE</CompressionType><NumBands Sync="TRUE">1</NumBands><Format Sync="TRUE">IMAGINE Image</Format><HasPyramids Sync="TRUE">TRUE</HasPyramids><SourceType Sync="TRUE">discrete</SourceType><PixelType Sync="TRUE">unsigned integer</PixelType><NoDataValue Sync="TRUE">256</NoDataValue></General></RasterProperties></DataProperties><SyncDate>20160126</SyncDate><SyncTime>11184200</SyncTime><ModDate>20160126</ModDate><ModTime>11213100</ModTime><ArcGISProfile>FGDC</ArcGISProfile></Esri><mdLang><languageCode value="eng"/><countryCode value="USA" Sync="TRUE"/></mdLang><mdChar><CharSetCd value="004"/></mdChar><mdHrLv><ScopeCd value="005"/></mdHrLv><mdContact><rpOrgName>U.S. Geological Survey</rpOrgName><rpPosName>Customer Services Representative</rpPosName><rpCntInfo><cntPhone><voiceNum>605/594-6151</voiceNum><voiceNum tddtty="True">605/594-6933</voiceNum><faxNum>605/594-6589</faxNum></cntPhone><cntAddress addressType="both"><delPoint>47914 252nd Street</delPoint><delPoint>USGS/EROS</delPoint><city>Sioux Falls</city><adminArea>SD</adminArea><postCode>57198-0001</postCode><country>US</country><eMailAdd>custserv@usgs.gov</eMailAdd></cntAddress><cntHours>0800 - 1600 CT, M - F (-6h CST/-5h CDT GMT)</cntHours><cntInstr>The USGS point of contact is for questions relating to the data display and download from this web site. For questions regarding data content and quality, refer to: &lt;http://www.mrlc.gov/mrlc2k.asp&gt; or email: mrlc@usgs.gov</cntInstr></rpCntInfo><role><RoleCd value="007"/></role></mdContact><mdDateSt Sync="TRUE">20160126</mdDateSt><mdStanName>ArcGIS Metadata</mdStanName><mdStanVer>1.0</mdStanVer><distInfo><distributor><distorCont><rpOrgName>U.S. Geological Survey</rpOrgName><rpPosName>Customer Services Representative</rpPosName><rpCntInfo><cntPhone><voiceNum>605-594-6151</voiceNum><voiceNum tddtty="True">605/594-6933</voiceNum><faxNum>605-594-6589</faxNum></cntPhone><cntAddress addressType="both"><delPoint>USGS/EROS</delPoint><delPoint>47914 252nd Street</delPoint><city>Sioux Falls</city><adminArea>SD</adminArea><postCode>57198-0001</postCode><country>US</country><eMailAdd>custserv@usgs.gov</eMailAdd></cntAddress><cntHours>0800 - 1600 CT, M - F (-6h CST/-5h CDT GMT)</cntHours><cntInstr>The USGS point of contact is for questions relating to the data display and download from this web site. For questions regarding data content and quality, refer to: &lt;http://www.mrlc.gov/mrlc2k.asp&gt; or email: mrlc@usgs.gov</cntInstr></rpCntInfo><role><RoleCd value="005"/></role></distorCont></distributor><distFormat><formatName Sync="TRUE">Raster Dataset</formatName></distFormat></distInfo><dataIdInfo><idCitation xmlns=""><resTitle Sync="FALSE">Puerto Rico and the US Virgin Islands NLCD2011 USFS Percent Tree Canopy Cover (Analytical Version)</resTitle><date><pubDate>2016-01-31</pubDate></date><resEd>1.0</resEd><citRespParty><rpOrgName>U.S. Geological Survey</rpOrgName><rpCntInfo><cntAddress><delPoint>USGS/EROS, Sioux Falls, SD, 57198-0001, US, 47914 252nd Street</delPoint></cntAddress></rpCntInfo><role><RoleCd value="010"/></role></citRespParty><presForm xmlns=""><PresFormCd value="005"/></presForm><presForm xmlns=""><fgdcGeoform>raster digital data</fgdcGeoform></presForm><datasetSeries><seriesName>none</seriesName><issId>none</issId></datasetSeries><otherCitDet>References: Baig, M.H.A., L. Zhang, T. Shuai, and Q. Tong, 2014. Derivation of a tasselled cap transformation based on Landsat 8 at-satellite reflectance, Remote Sensing Letters, 5(5):423-431. Brand, G.J., M.D. Nelson, D.G. Wendt, and K.K. Nimerfro, 2000. The hexagon/panel system for selecting FIA plots under an annual inventory. In: McRoberts, R. E., G.A. Reams, and P.C. Van Deusen, eds. Proceedings of the First Annual Forest Inventory and Analysis Symposium; Gen. Tech. Rep. NC-213. St. Paul, MN: U.S. Department of Agriculture, Forest Service, North Central Research Station: 8-13. Breiman, L. 2001. Random forests. Machine Learning 45:15-32. Coulston, J.W., D.M. Jacobs, C.R. King, and I.C. Elmore, 2013. The influence of multi-season imagery on models of canopy cover: a case study. Photogrammetric Engineering &amp; Remote Sensing 79(5):469-477. Coulston, J.W., G.G. Moisen, B.T. Wilson, M.V. Finco, W.B. Cohen, C.K. Brewer, 2012. Modeling percent tree canopy cover: a pilot study. Photogrammetric Engineering &amp; Remote Sensing 78(7):715-727. Cutler, R.D., T.C. Edwards, K.H. Beard, A. Cutler, K.T. Hess, J. Gibson, and J.J. Lawler, 2007. Random forest for classification in ecology. Ecology 88 (11):2783-2792. Huang, C., L. Yang, B. Wylie, and C. Homer, 2001. A strategy for estimating tree canopy density using Landsat 7 ETM+ and high resolution images over large areas. In: Third International Conference on Geospatial Information in Agriculture and Forestry; November 5-7, 2001; Denver, Colorado. CD-ROM, 1 disk. Liaw, A. and M. Wiener, 2002. Classification and regression by randomForest. R News. 2(3): 18-22. McRoberts, R.E., M.H. Hansen, 1999. Annual forest inventories for the north central region of the United States. Journal of Agricultural, Biological, and Environmental Statistics. 4(4): 361-371. Moisen, G.G., J.W. Coulston, B.T. Wilson, W.B. Cohen, and M.V. Finco, 2012. Choosing appropriate subpopulations for modeling tree canopy cover nationwide. In: McWilliams, Will; Roesch, Francis A., eds. 2012. Monitoring Across Borders: 2010 Joint Meeting of the Forest Inventory and Analysis (FIA) Symposium and the Southern Mensurationists. e-Gen. Tech. Rep. SRS-157. Asheville, NC: U.S. Department of Agriculture, Forest Service, Southern Research Station: 195-200. Nowacki, G, P. Spencer, M. Fleming, T. Brock, and T. Jorgenson, 2001. Ecoregions of Alaska: 2001. U.S. Geological Survey. Open-File Report 02-297 (map). R Core Team, 2013. R: A language and environment for statistical computing. Vienna, Austria: R Foundation for Statistical Computing. http://www.R-project.org. (Accessed: 24 Feb 2015.) Ruefenacht, B., 2016. Using Landsat-5 TM composites to model percent tree canopy cover. Photogrammetric Engineering &amp; Remote Sensing (In Press). Tipton, J., G.Moisen, P. Patterson, T.A. Jackson, and J. Coulston, 2012. Sampling intensity and normalizations: Exploring cost-driving factors in nationwide mapping of tree canopy cover. In: McWilliams, Will; Roesch, Francis A., eds. 2012. Monitoring Across Borders: 2010 Joint Meeting of the Forest Inventory and Analysis (FIA) Symposium and the Southern Mensurationists. e-Gen. Tech. Rep. SRS-157. Asheville, NC: U.S. Department of Agriculture, Forest Service, Southern Research Station: 201-208. Zhu, Z. and C.E. Woodcock, 2012. Object-based cloud and cloud shadow detection in Landsat imagery. Remote Sensing of Environment. 118(2012): 83-94.</otherCitDet></idCitation><idAbs>&lt;DIV STYLE="text-align:Left;"&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The National Land Cover Database 2011 (NLCD2011) percent tree canopy cover layer (TCC 2011) was produced through a cooperative project conducted by the Multi-Resolution Land Characteristics (MRLC) Consortium (www.mrlc.gov). The MRLC Consortium is a partnership of federal agencies, consisting of the U.S. Geological Survey, the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, the U.S. Environmental Protection Agency, the U.S. Department of Agriculture (USDA) National Agricultural Statistics Service, the U.S. Forest Service, the National Park Service, the U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service, the Bureau of Land Management, NASA, and the U.S. Army Corps of Engineers. One of the primary goals of the project was to generate a current, consistent, and seamless national land cover, percent tree canopy cover, and percent impervious cover at medium spatial resolution. Puerto Rico and the US Virgin Islands TCC 2011 was produced by the USDA Forest Service Remote Sensing Applications Center (RSAC). The Puerto Rico and the US Virgin Islands TCC 2011 dataset has two layers: percent tree canopy cover (PTCC) and standard error. For the PTCC layer, the pixel values range from 0 to 100 percent. For the standard error layer, the pixel values range from 0 to 45 percent. For both layers, 255 represents the background value. The standard error represents the model uncertainty associated with the corresponding pixel in the PTCC layer. The PTCC layer was produced using random forest and the standard error layer was calculated from the variance of the canopy cover estimates from the random forest regression trees. The PTCC has data gaps due to persistent clouds/shadows in the Landsat images used for modeling. These data gaps are represented by the number 127.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;</idAbs><idPurp>The goal of this project is to provide the Nation with complete, current and consistent public domain information on its tree canopy cover.</idPurp><idCredit>USDA Forest Service Remote Sensing Applications Center</idCredit><idPoC><rpOrgName>U.S. Geological Survey</rpOrgName><rpPosName>Customer Services Representative</rpPosName><rpCntInfo><cntPhone><voiceNum>605/594-6151</voiceNum><voiceNum tddtty="True">605/594-6933</voiceNum><faxNum>605/594-6589</faxNum></cntPhone><cntAddress addressType="both"><delPoint>USGS/EROS</delPoint><delPoint>47914 252nd Street</delPoint><city>Sioux Falls</city><adminArea>SD</adminArea><postCode>57198-0001</postCode><country>US</country><eMailAdd>custserv@usgs.gov</eMailAdd></cntAddress><cntHours>0800 - 1600 CT, M - F (-6h CST/-5h CDT GMT)</cntHours><cntInstr>The USGS point of contact is for questions relating to the data display and download from this web site. For questions regarding data content and quality, refer to: &lt;http://www.mrlc.gov/mrlc2k.asp&gt; or email: mrlc@usgs.gov</cntInstr></rpCntInfo><role><RoleCd value="007"/></role></idPoC><resMaint><maintFreq><MaintFreqCd value="009"/></maintFreq></resMaint><placeKeys><thesaName><resTitle>U.S. Department of Commerce, 1995, Countries, dependencies, areas of special sovereignty, and their principal administrative divisions, Federal Information Processing Standard 10-4: Washington, D.C., National Institute of Standards and Technology</resTitle></thesaName><keyword>U.S.</keyword><keyword>USVI</keyword><keyword>USA</keyword><keyword>United States of America</keyword><keyword>PR</keyword><keyword>US Virgin Islands</keyword><keyword>U.S. Virgin Islands</keyword><keyword>US</keyword><keyword>Puerto Rico</keyword><keyword>United States</keyword><keyword>U.S.A.</keyword></placeKeys><themeKeys><thesaName><resTitle>ISO 19115 Category</resTitle></thesaName><keyword>Earth Covers</keyword><keyword>Imagery</keyword><keyword>Base Map</keyword></themeKeys><themeKeys><keyword>GIS</keyword><keyword>Percent Tree Canopy</keyword><keyword>USFS</keyword><keyword>Tree Canopy Cover</keyword><keyword>Remote Sensing</keyword><keyword>Continuous</keyword><keyword>Digital Spatial Data</keyword><keyword>U.S. Forest Service</keyword></themeKeys><searchKeys><keyword>U.S.</keyword><keyword>USVI</keyword><keyword>Earth Covers</keyword><keyword>GIS</keyword><keyword>USA</keyword><keyword>United States of America</keyword><keyword>Percent Tree Canopy</keyword><keyword>Imagery</keyword><keyword>PR</keyword><keyword>US Virgin Islands</keyword><keyword>USFS</keyword><keyword>U.S. Virgin Islands</keyword><keyword>US</keyword><keyword>Puerto Rico</keyword><keyword>Tree Canopy Cover</keyword><keyword>Remote Sensing</keyword><keyword>United States</keyword><keyword>Continuous</keyword><keyword>Base Map</keyword><keyword>U.S.A.</keyword><keyword>Digital Spatial Data</keyword><keyword>U.S. Forest Service</keyword></searchKeys><resConst><LegConsts><useLimit>See access and use constraints information.</useLimit></LegConsts></resConst><resConst><SecConsts><class><ClasscationCd value="001"/></class></SecConsts></resConst><resConst><Consts><useLimit>&lt;DIV STYLE="text-align:Left;"&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Any hardcopy or electronic products utilizing these datasets will clearly indicate their source. If the user has modified the data in any way, they are obligated to describe the types of modifications they have performed. User specifically agrees not to misrepresent these data sets, nor to imply that the MRLC approved the changes. Any data downloaded must be properly cited.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;</useLimit></Consts></resConst><dataLang><languageCode value="eng"/><countryCode value="USA" Sync="TRUE"/></dataLang><envirDesc Sync="TRUE">Microsoft Windows 7 Version 6.1 (Build 7601) Service Pack 1; ESRI ArcGIS 10.0.5.4400</envirDesc><dataExt><geoEle><GeoBndBox><westBL>-69.628175</westBL><eastBL>-62.422481</eastBL><southBL>15.177592</southBL><northBL>20.8712</northBL></GeoBndBox></geoEle></dataExt><dataExt><exDesc>Ground condition at time of imagery capture</exDesc><tempEle><TempExtent><exTemp><TM_Period><tmBegin>2013-11-11</tmBegin><tmEnd>2015-02-25</tmEnd></TM_Period></exTemp></TempExtent></tempEle></dataExt><suppInfo>Corner Coordinates (center of pixel, meters): upper left: 2890755 (X), 189555 (Y); lower right: 3591885 (X), -219375 (Y).</suppInfo><spatRpType><SpatRepTypCd value="002" Sync="TRUE"/></spatRpType><dataExt><geoEle><GeoBndBox esriExtentType="search"><exTypeCode Sync="TRUE">1</exTypeCode><westBL Sync="TRUE">-67.950181</westBL><eastBL Sync="TRUE">-64.398022</eastBL><northBL Sync="TRUE">19.319894</northBL><southBL Sync="TRUE">17.013923</southBL></GeoBndBox></geoEle></dataExt><dataChar><CharSetCd value="004"></CharSetCd></dataChar><tpCat><TopicCatCd value="010"/></tpCat></dataIdInfo><dqInfo xmlns=""><dqScope><scpLvl><ScopeCd value="005"/></scpLvl></dqScope><report type="DQCompOm" dimension="" xmlns=""><measDesc>This Puerto Rico and the US Virgin Islands TCC 2011 product is version 1, dated 2016. The Puerto Rico and the US Virgin Islands TCC 2011 dataset consists of two main data products: (1) per-pixel tree canopy cover and (2) per- pixel standard error for the predicted tree canopy cover. A summary of all the Landsat images and the significant predictor variables used for modeling tree canopy cover with the random forest regression algorithm is available in the supplemental metadata. For detailed information, please refer to &lt;http://www.mrlc.gov&gt;.</measDesc></report><report type="DQQuanAttAcc" dimension="" xmlns=""><measDesc>No formal independent accuracy assessment of the Puerto Rico and the US Virgin Islands TCC 2011 has been made. The random forest regression algorithm (Breiman 2001; Liaw and Wiener 2002; Cutler et al. 2007) employed in the Puerto Rico and the US Virgin Islands TCC 2011 mapping calculates the mean of squared residuals along with percent variability explained by the model for assessing prediction reliability. The random forest models consisted of 500 decision trees, which were used to determine the final response value. The response of each tree depended on a randomly chosen subset of predictor variables chosen independently (with replacement) for evaluation by that tree. The responses of the trees were averaged to obtain an estimate of the dependent variable. The standard error is the square root of the variance of the estimates given by all trees. A summary of the random forest model is available in the supplemental metadata.</measDesc></report><dataLineage><prcStep><stepDesc>Creation of percent tree canopy cover dataset (main process). The NLCD 2011 percent tree canopy cover (TCC 2011) for Puerto Rico and the US Virgin Islands was created as a single model using six Landsat WRS-2 path/rows. Five major steps were employed to map tree canopy cover: 1) collection of reference data, 2) acquisition and/or creation of predictor layers, 3) calibration of the random forest regression models using response data and predictor layers, 4) application of those models to predict per-pixel tree canopy cover across Puerto Rico and the US Virgin Islands, and 5) creation of the Puerto Rico and the US Virgin Islands mosaic. The methodology is described further below and in Coulston et al. (2012) and Ruefenacht (2016). Response data, consisting of estimated tree canopy cover at each of 990 plot locations, were generated via photographic interpretation (PI) of high spatial resolution images, as described in the Photointerpretation of Sample Plots process step. Predictor layers included Landsat 8 OLI composite imagery, Landsat spectral derivatives (NDMI, NDVI, and tasseled cap), NLCD 2001 land cover, and explicit location data (x,y). Modeling was carried out using the random forest algorithm as implemented in R (Liaw and Wiener, 2002; R Core Team, 2013) as outlined in the Attribute Accuracy Report above. The random forest model trained from the response data was applied to the predictor data layers for each Landsat WRS-2 path/row encompassing Puerto Rico and the US Virgin Islands producing a 2-layered image. The first layer was the random forest estimate of percent tree canopy cover and the second layer was the standard error, which is the per-pixel square root of the variance of the random forest estimates from the individual trees.</stepDesc><stepDateTm>2015-11-12</stepDateTm><stepSrc type="used"><srcCitatn><resAltTitle>PI_CC, L8Comp, NDMI, NDVI, TasCap, XCoord, YCoord</resAltTitle></srcCitatn></stepSrc></prcStep><prcStep><stepDesc>Creation of Landsat derivatives. Spectral derivative images were calculated from the Landsat composite image for each WRS-2 path/row. NDMI (normalized difference moisture index), NDVI (normalized difference vegetation index), and tasseled cap transformation (Baig et al. 2014) were calculated following industry standards.</stepDesc><stepDateTm>2015-06-30</stepDateTm><stepSrc type="produced"><srcCitatn><resAltTitle>NDMI, NDVI, TasCap</resAltTitle></srcCitatn></stepSrc></prcStep><prcStep><stepDesc>Photointerpretation of Sample Plots. Response data used to train the computer models is made by photographic interpretation of sample plots. Each plot representing approximately 950 hectares is part of a national hexagonal grid which covers all land types and is considered an equal probability sample for the total surface area (McRoberts et al., 1999). There are 990 plots encompassed by Puerto Rico and the US Virgin Islands. A circle with a radius of 43.9 m (144 ft.) was placed over each plot center. Each circle contained a 109-dot grid oriented 15 degrees east of true north with each dot separated by 8 m. Photo-interpreters evaluated each dot as being either tree or not tree. For each plot, fractional tree canopy cover was calculated as the number of dots attributed tree divided by 109. The imagery upon which the photo interpreters based their observations was an orthographic aerial image mosaic acquired by the U.S. Army Corps of Engineers. The aerial imagery was provided to the TCC Project by the USDA Natural Resources Conservation Service (NRCS) National Geospatial Center of Excellence (NGCE). Image tiles within the mosaic were circa 2009 through 2012.</stepDesc><stepDateTm>2015-09-11</stepDateTm><stepSrc type="produced"><srcCitatn><resAltTitle>PI</resAltTitle></srcCitatn></stepSrc></prcStep><prcStep><stepDesc>Creation of Landsat composite. Multiple Landsat 8 scenes were selected and processed for each WRS-2 path/row. Selected scenes were acquired between 2013 and 2015. The selection process favored scenes with minimal cloud cover. An automated cloud masking algorithm, Fmask, (Zhu and Woodcock 2012) was used to remove clouds from each scene. Eight spectral bands (OLI bands 1-7 and 9) within each scene were transformed to surface reflectance (http://landsat.usgs.gov/Landsat8_Using_Product.php). A median value was calculated using all available pixel values for each geolocation (Ruefenacht 2016). These median values were combined to create a composite image for each path/row.</stepDesc><stepDateTm>2015-06-17</stepDateTm><stepSrc type="used"><srcCitatn><resAltTitle>L8</resAltTitle></srcCitatn></stepSrc><stepSrc type="produced"><srcCitatn><resAltTitle>L8Comp</resAltTitle></srcCitatn></stepSrc></prcStep><dataSource><srcDesc>spectral information</srcDesc><srcCitatn><resTitle>Landsat 8 Operational Land Imager (OLI) Imagery</resTitle><resAltTitle>L8</resAltTitle><citRespParty><rpOrgName>U.S. Geological Survey</rpOrgName><rpCntInfo><cntAddress><delPoint>Sioux Falls, SD</delPoint></cntAddress></rpCntInfo><role><RoleCd value="010"/></role></citRespParty><presForm><PresFormCd value="005"/></presForm><presForm><fgdcGeoform>raster digital data</fgdcGeoform></presForm></srcCitatn></dataSource><dataSource><srcDesc>canopy cover estimate (training/validation)</srcDesc><srcCitatn><resTitle>Photointerpreted Canopy Cover</resTitle><resAltTitle>PI_CC</resAltTitle><citRespParty><rpOrgName>USDA Forest Service Remote Sensing Applications Center</rpOrgName><role><RoleCd value="006"/></role></citRespParty><presForm><PresFormCd value="005"/></presForm><presForm><fgdcGeoform>vector digital data</fgdcGeoform></presForm></srcCitatn></dataSource><dataSource><srcDesc>east-west location (relative to 96.0 W longitude)</srcDesc><srcCitatn><resTitle>X-Coordinate</resTitle><resAltTitle>XCoord</resAltTitle><citRespParty><rpOrgName>USDA Forest Service Remote Sensing Applications Center</rpOrgName><role><RoleCd value="006"/></role></citRespParty><presForm><PresFormCd value="005"/></presForm><presForm><fgdcGeoform>raster digital data</fgdcGeoform></presForm></srcCitatn></dataSource><dataSource><srcDesc>north-south location (relative to 37.5 N latitude)</srcDesc><srcCitatn><resTitle>Y-Coordinate</resTitle><resAltTitle>YCoord</resAltTitle><citRespParty><rpOrgName>USDA Forest Service Remote Sensing Applications Center</rpOrgName><role><RoleCd value="006"/></role></citRespParty><presForm><PresFormCd value="005"/></presForm><presForm><fgdcGeoform>raster digital data</fgdcGeoform></presForm></srcCitatn></dataSource></dataLineage></dqInfo><spatRepInfo><Georect><numDims Sync="TRUE">2</numDims><axisDimension type="001"><dimSize Sync="TRUE">4656</dimSize><dimResol><value Sync="TRUE" uom="Meter">30.000000</value></dimResol></axisDimension><axisDimension type="002"><dimSize Sync="TRUE">12176</dimSize><dimResol><value Sync="TRUE" uom="Meter">30.000000</value></dimResol></axisDimension><cellGeo><CellGeoCd value="002" Sync="TRUE"/></cellGeo><tranParaAv Sync="TRUE">1</tranParaAv><chkPtAv Sync="TRUE">0</chkPtAv><cornerPts><pos Sync="TRUE">3042585.000000 -78285.000000</pos></cornerPts><cornerPts><pos Sync="TRUE">3042585.000000 61395.000000</pos></cornerPts><cornerPts><pos Sync="TRUE">3407865.000000 61395.000000</pos></cornerPts><cornerPts><pos Sync="TRUE">3407865.000000 -78285.000000</pos></cornerPts><centerPt><pos Sync="TRUE">3225225.000000 -8445.000000</pos></centerPt><ptInPixel><PixOrientCd Sync="TRUE" value="001"/></ptInPixel></Georect></spatRepInfo><eainfo><detailed Name="nlcd2011_usfs_prusvi_canopy_analytical.img.vat" xmlns=""><enttyp><enttypl Sync="TRUE">nlcd2011_usfs_prusvi_canopy_analytical.img.vat</enttypl><enttypt Sync="TRUE">Table</enttypt><enttypc Sync="TRUE">256</enttypc></enttyp><attr xmlns=""><attrlabl Sync="TRUE">OID</attrlabl><attalias Sync="TRUE">OID</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">OID</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">4</attwidth><atprecis Sync="TRUE">0</atprecis><attscale Sync="TRUE">0</attscale><attrdef Sync="TRUE">Internal feature number.</attrdef><attrdefs Sync="TRUE">ESRI</attrdefs><attrdomv><udom Sync="TRUE">Sequential unique whole numbers that are automatically generated.</udom></attrdomv></attr><attr xmlns=""><attrlabl Sync="TRUE">Value</attrlabl><attalias Sync="TRUE">Value</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">Integer</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">0</attwidth><atprecis Sync="TRUE">0</atprecis><attscale Sync="TRUE">0</attscale><attrdomv><udom> 127 = No data available 255 = Background</udom></attrdomv></attr><attr xmlns=""><attrlabl Sync="TRUE">Count</attrlabl><attalias Sync="TRUE">Count</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">Double</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">0</attwidth><atprecis Sync="TRUE">0</atprecis><attscale Sync="TRUE">0</attscale></attr><attr xmlns=""><attrlabl Sync="TRUE">Red</attrlabl><attalias Sync="TRUE">Red</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">Double</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">0</attwidth><atprecis Sync="TRUE">0</atprecis><attscale Sync="TRUE">0</attscale></attr><attr xmlns=""><attrlabl Sync="TRUE">Green</attrlabl><attalias Sync="TRUE">Green</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">Double</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">0</attwidth><atprecis Sync="TRUE">0</atprecis><attscale Sync="TRUE">0</attscale></attr><attr xmlns=""><attrlabl Sync="TRUE">Blue</attrlabl><attalias Sync="TRUE">Blue</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">Double</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">0</attwidth><atprecis Sync="TRUE">0</atprecis><attscale Sync="TRUE">0</attscale></attr><attr xmlns=""><attrlabl Sync="TRUE">Opacity</attrlabl><attalias Sync="TRUE">Opacity</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">Double</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">0</attwidth><atprecis Sync="TRUE">0</atprecis><attscale Sync="TRUE">0</attscale></attr></detailed></eainfo><mdHrLvName Sync="TRUE">dataset</mdHrLvName><refSysInfo><RefSystem><refSysID><identCode code="0" Sync="TRUE" value="0"/></refSysID></RefSystem></refSysInfo><contInfo><ImgDesc><contentTyp><ContentTypCd Sync="TRUE" value="002"/></contentTyp><covDim><Band><dimDescrp Sync="TRUE">Layer_1</dimDescrp><maxVal Sync="TRUE">255.000000</maxVal><minVal Sync="TRUE">1.000000</minVal><bitsPerVal Sync="TRUE">8</bitsPerVal><valUnit><UOM type="length"><unitSymbol Sync="TRUE">Meter</unitSymbol></UOM></valUnit></Band></covDim></ImgDesc></contInfo></metadata>
